Guide to the American Veterans Committee records, 1942-2002 MS2144
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Events, 1946-2000; MS2144 Series 8
  - Conference on Education and Returning Vietnam Veterans, 1972 (Box 175, Folder 5)
  - Congressman Peter W. Rodino, Jr. Reception, 1975 (Box 175, Folder 6)
  - NAACP Summit Conference and Luncheon Program, 1975 (Box 175, Folder 7)
  - Chicago Area Council AVC Dinner, 04/07/1979 (Box 176, Folder 1)
  - The Citizen Soldier Conference, 1979 (Box 176, Folder 2)
  - The Fashion Industry Salutes the Woman Veteran - Reception and Dinner Dance, 1981 (Box 176, Folder 3)
  - The Search for Global Security Conference, 1981 (Box 176, Folder 4)
  - Gus Tyler's 70th Birthday Dinner, 1981 (Box 176, Folder 5)
  - Gus Tyler's 70th Birthday Dinner, 11/06/1981; Series 8 (Box 259, Folder 15)
  - Citizens First Award Dinner, 1982 (Box 176, Folder 6)
  - Chicago Area Chapters AVC 38th reunion & cocktail party, 05/16/1983; Series 8 (Box 259, Folder 14)
  - Health Panel, 06/26/1983 (Box 176, Folder 7)
  - Christmas of '43 Party, 12/19/1983 (Box 176, Folder 8)
  - Robert Nathan's 75th Birthday and Award Presentation, 1984 (Box 176, Folder 9)
  - National Women Veterans Recognition Week Kick-Off Observation of S.J. Res. 227, 1984 (Box 176, Folder 10)
  - Human Rights Day Community Luncheon, 1984 (Box 176, Folder 11)
  - United Nations Conference on Women, 1985 (Box 176, Folder 12)
  - Citizens First Awards Dinner, 1985 (Box 176, Folder 13)
  - "War Veterans and International Humanitarian Law - Yesterday, Today, Tomorrow" Symposium, 03/1986 (Box 176, Folder 14)
  - Salute to Sol (Chick) Chaikin, 04/06/1986 (Box 176, Folder 15)
  - Holiday Season Open House, 12/11/1987 (Box 176, Folder 16)
  - National Vietnam Veterans Readjustment Study Panel, 1989 (Box 176, Folder 17)
  - Dialogue on National Service A National Conference, 1989 (Box 176, Folder 18)
  - National Foreign Policy Conference for Leaders of Nongovernmental Organizations, 10/23/1989 (Box 176, Folder 19)
  - White House briefing on Russia and Emerging Democracies, 06/09/1992 (Box 176, Folder 20)
  - Women's Research and Education Institute Conference on Women Veterans, 12/08/1993 (Box 177, Folder 1)
  - William Joiner Center Conference, 05/01/1994 (Box 177, Folder 2)
  - White House Conference on Aging, 05/1995 (Box 177, Folder 3)
  - Unknown events, undated (Box 177, Folder 4)
  - 9th National Conference (Atlantic City) (OVERSIZE), 11/1955 (Box 178, Folder 1)
  - 10th National Conference (Washington, DC) (OVERSIZE), 04/1957 (Box 178, Folder 2)
  - 15th Anniversary Convention (Pocono Manor, PA) (OVERSIZE), 04/25/1958-04/27/1958 (Box 179, Folder 1)
  - 17th National Convention (New York, NY) (OVERSIZE), 05/1964 (Box 179, Folder 2)
  - 18th National Convention (Atlantic City, NJ) (OVERSIZE), 06/1965 (Box 179, Folder 3)
- Local chapters, 1946-2001; MS2144 Series 9
  This series includes correspondence, newsletters, and lists relating to the membership and activities of local AVC chapters. A majority of the material in this series comes from the Washington, DC, and Chicago chapters. It is arranged alphabetically by the state in which the chapter was located.
  Chapters include: Tuskegee, AL Little Rock, AR Los Angeles, CA San Francisco, CA Washington, DC Delaware Valley, DE Miami, FL Paris, France Chicago, IL Indianapolis, IN Harvard University (MA) Ann Arbor, MI St. Paul, MN Minneapolis, MN Jackson, MS St. Louis, MO Bronx, NY Brooklyn, NY Laurelton-Rosedale, NY Manhattan, NY Riverside, NY Cleveland, OH Portland, OR Tulsa, OK Seattle, WA Milwaukee, WI
  - Tuskegee, AL Chapter, 1960-1969 (Box 180, Folder 1)
  - Little Rock, Ark. Chapter: Newsletter, undated (Box 180, Folder 2)
  - Los Angeles, California Chapter, 1940-1949 (Box 180, Folder 3)
  - Los Angeles, California Chapter [1/3], 1946-1949 (Box 180, Folder 4)
  - Los Angeles, California Chapter [2/3], 1946-1949 (Box 180, Folder 5)
  - Los Angeles, California Chapter [3/3], 1946-1949 (Box 180, Folder 6)
  - Los Angeles, California Chapter, 1950-1959 (Box 180, Folder 7)
  - Los Angeles, California Chapter, 1983-1996 (Box 254, Folder 3)
  - Los Angeles, California Chapter: Newsletter, undated (Box 180, Folder 8)
  - San Francisco, California Chapter, 1940-1949 (Box 180, Folder 9)
  - San Francisco Bay Area, California Chapter, 1960-2001 (Box 254, Folder 4)
  - San Francisco Bay Area, California Chapter: Newsletter, 1960-1962 (Box 254, Folder 5)
  - Washington, DC Chapter [1/2], 1946-1949 (Box 180, Folder 10)
  - Washington, DC Chapter [2/2], 1946-1949 (Box 180, Folder 11)
  - Washington D.C. Chapter, 1950-1959 (Box 181, Folder 1)
  - Washington D.C. Chapter, 1950-1959 (Box 181, Folder 2)
  - Washington D.C. Chapter, 1960-1969 (Box 181, Folder 3)
  - Washington D.C. Chapter, 1970-1979 (Box 181, Folder 4)
  - Washington D.C. Chapter, 1960-1969 (Box 181, Folder 5)
  - Washington D.C. Chapter, 1970-1979 (Box 181, Folder 6)
  - Washington D.C.: Dues, 1970-1982 (Box 181, Folder 7)
  - Washington D.C. Chapter, 1980-1989 (Box 181, Folder 8)
  - Washington D.C. Chapter, 1990-1999 (Box 181, Folder 9)
  - Washington D.C. Chapter, 08/14/1999; Series 9 (Box 259, Folder 16)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter: Correspondence, clippings (#1), 1990-1999 (Box 182, Folder 1)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter, 1990-1999 (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter, 2000-2001 (Box 182, Folder 3)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter: Cap Vets, 1946-1976 (Box 182, Folder 4)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter: Cap Vets, 1960-1969 (Box 182, Folder 5)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter: Cap Vets, 1970-1979 (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter: Cap Vet Binder, 1975-1980 (Box 182, Folder 7)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter: Cap Vets [1/2], 1980-1989 (Box 182, Folder 8)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter: Cap Vets [2/2], 1980-1989 (Box 182, Folder 9)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter: Cap Vets, 1990-1999 (Box 182, Folder 10)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter: Cap Vets, 1990-1999 (Box 183, Folder 1)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter: Cap Vets, 2001 (Box 183, Folder 2)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter: Cap Vets, 2002-2006 (Box 254, Folder 6)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter: Civil Rights, undated (Box 183, Folder 3)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter: Membership List, undated (Box 183, Folder 4)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter: Membership Reports, 1961-1978 (Box 183, Folder 5)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter: Addresses, undated (Box 183, Folder 6)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter: Members Addresses, undated (Box 183, Folder 7)
  - Washington, D.C. Chapter Dues, undated (Box 183, Folder 8)
  - Delaware Valley, DEL Chapter #918, 1962 (Box 254, Folder 7)
  - Delaware Valley, DEL Chapter #918, 1970-1979 (Box 183, Folder 9)
  - Miami, FL Chapter, 1947 (Box 183, Folder 10)
  - Paris, France Chapter, 1946-1949 (Box 183, Folder 11)
  - Paris, France Chapter: Charter, 1948 (Box 183, Folder 12)
  - Paris, France Chapter, 1946-1949 (Box 184, Folder 1)
  - Paris, France Chapter, 1950-1959 (Box 184, Folder 2)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter [1/4], 1946-1949 (Box 184, Folder 3)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter [2/4], 1946-1949 (Box 184, Folder 4)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter [3/4], 1946-1949 (Box 184, Folder 5)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter [4/4], 1946-1949 (Box 184, Folder 6)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter: National Convention, 1949 (Box 184, Folder 7)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter, 1946-1949 (Box 185, Folder 1)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter [1/2], 1950-1959 (Box 185, Folder 2)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter [2/2], 1950-1959 (Box 185, Folder 3)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter [1/2], 1960-1969 (Box 185, Folder 4)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter [2/2], 1960-1969 (Box 185, Folder 5)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter, 1970-1979 (Box 185, Folder 6)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter, 1980-1989 (Box 186, Folder 1)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter [1/3], 1990-1999 (Box 186, Folder 2)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter [2/3], 1990-1999 (Box 186, Folder 3)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter [3/3], 1990-1999 (Box 186, Folder 4)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter, 1993-1999; Series 9 (Box 259, Folder 17)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter, 2000-2001 (Box 186, Folder 5)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter, 2002-2004 (Box 254, Folder 8)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter: Ten Strike, 1946-1949 (Box 186, Folder 6)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter: Ten Strike, 1950-1959 (Box 186, Folder 7)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter: Ten Strike, 1960-1969 (Box 186, Folder 8)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter: Finances, 1983-1977 (Box 254, Folder 9)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter: Members Addresses/Dues [1/4], undated (Box 186, Folder 9)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter: Members Addresses/Dues [2/4], undated (Box 186, Folder 10)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter: Members Addresses/Dues [3/4], undated (Box 186, Folder 11)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter: Members Addresses/Dues [4/4], undated (Box 186, Folder 12)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter: Obituaries, undated (Box 186, Folder 13)
  - Chicago, IL Chapter: Tibor Heisler Awards, 1968-1996 (Box 254, Folder 10)
  - Indianapolis, Indiana Chapter (#134), 1948-1965 (Box 187, Folder 1)
  - Harvard University Chapter [1/3], 1946-1949 (Box 187, Folder 2)
  - Harvard University Chapter [2/3], 1946-1949 (Box 187, Folder 3)
  - Harvard University Chapter [3/3], 1946-1949 (Box 187, Folder 4)
  - Harvard University Chapter, 1950-1959 (Box 187, Folder 5)
  - Harvard University Chapter: Newsletter, undated (Box 187, Folder 6)
  - Harvard University Chapter: Members Addresses/Dues, undated (Box 187, Folder 7)
  - Massachusetts Veteran (newspaper), 1959 (Box 187, Folder 8)
  - Ann Arbor/Detroit, MI Chapters, 1948-1951 (Box 187, Folder 9)
  - St. Paul/Minneapolis, Minn. Chapters (#157, 18), 1946-1949 (Box 187, Folder 10)
  - St. Paul/Minneapolis, Minn. Chapters (#157, 18), 1950-1959 (Box 188, Folder 1)
  - St. Paul, Minn. Chapter (#157): AV Citizen Newsletter, undated (Box 188, Folder 2)
  - Jackson, Mississippi Chapter (#319), 1946-1949 (Box 188, Folder 3)
  - Jackson, Mississippi Chapter (#319), 1950-1959 (Box 188, Folder 4)
  - Jackson, Mississippi Chapter (#319) [1/4], 1960-1969 (Box 188, Folder 5)
  - Jackson, Mississippi Chapter (#319) [2/4], 1960-1969 (Box 188, Folder 6)
  - Jackson, Mississippi Chapter (#319) [3/4], 1960-1969 (Box 188, Folder 7)
  - Jackson, Mississippi Chapter (#319) [4/4], 1960-1969 (Box 188, Folder 8)
  - Jackson, Mississippi Chapter (#319), 1970-1979 (Box 188, Folder 9)
  - Jackson, Mississippi Chapter (#319), 1980-1989 (Box 188, Folder 10)
  - Jackson, Mississippi Chapter (#319): Members Addresses/Dues, undated (Box 188, Folder 11)
  - Jackson, Mississippi Chapter (#319): Members Addresses/Dues [1/3], undated (Box 189, Folder 1)
  - Jackson, Mississippi Chapter (#319): Members Addresses/Dues [2/3], undated (Box 189, Folder 2)
  - Jackson, Mississippi Chapter (#319): Members Addresses/Dues [3/3], undated (Box 189, Folder 3)
  - St. Louis, MO Chapter, 1950-1959 (Box 189, Folder 4)
  - Bronx, NY Chapter - F.D.R. (#9): Members Addresses/Dues [1/2], undated (Box 189, Folder 5)
  - Bronx, NY Chapter - F.D.R. (#9): Members Addresses/Dues [2/2], undated (Box 189, Folder 6)
  - Bronx, NY Chapter: F.D.R. Digest, undated (Box 189, Folder 7)
  - Bronx, NY Chapter: F.D.R. (#9), 1946-1982 (Box 189, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn, New York Chapter (#31), 1946-1949 (Box 189, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn, New York Chapter (#31), 1950-1959 (Box 189, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn, New York Chapter (#31), 1960-1969 (Box 189, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn, New York Chapter (#31), 1970-1979 (Box 190, Folder 1)
  - Brooklyn, New York Chapter (#31): The Observer, 1949 (Box 190, Folder 2)
  - Brooklyn, New York Chapter (#31): Members Addresses/Dues, undated (Box 190, Folder 3)
  - Laurelton-Rosedale, NY Chapter (#100), 1946-1949 (Box 190, Folder 4)
  - Laurelton-Rosedale, NY Chapter (#100) [1/2], 1950-1959 (Box 190, Folder 5)
  - Laurelton-Rosedale, NY Chapter (#100) [2/2], 1950-1959 (Box 190, Folder 6)
  - Laurelton-Rosedale, NY Chapter (#100) [1/2], 1960-1969 (Box 190, Folder 7)
  - Laurelton-Rosedale, NY Chapter (#100) [2/2], 1960-1969 (Box 190, Folder 8)
  - Laurelton-Rosedale, NY Chapter (#100), 1970-1983 (Box 190, Folder 9)
  - Laurelton-Rosedale, NY Chapter (#100): Report Newsletter, undated (Box 190, Folder 10)
  - Laurelton-Rosedale, NY Chapter (#100): Members Addresses, undated (Box 191, Folder 1)
  - Laurelton-Rosedale, NY Chapter (#100): Members Addresses/Dues, undated (Box 191, Folder 2)
  - Laurelton-Rosedale, NY Chapter: Members Addresses/Dues [1/2], undated (Box 191, Folder 3)
  - Laurelton-Rosedale, NY Chapter: Members Addresses/Dues [2/2], undated (Box 191, Folder 4)
  - Manhattan, NY Chapter (#28), 1946-1984 (Box 191, Folder 5)
  - Manhattan, NY Chapter (#28): Members Addresses/Dues, undated (Box 191, Folder 6)
  - Riverside, NY Chapter (#52), undated (Box 191, Folder 7)
  - Various New York Chapters: Membership Transmittal Forms, 1970-1979 (Box 191, Folder 8)
  - Various New York Chapters: Membership Transmittal Forms, 1980-1989 (Box 191, Folder 9)
  - Cleveland, OH Chapter, 1950-1959 (Box 191, Folder 10)
  - Portland, OR Chapter (#174): Newsletter, undated (Box 191, Folder 11)
  - Tulsa, OK and all Southwest, 1946-1950 (Box 192, Folder 1)
  - Tulsa, OK Chapter: Newsletter [1/2], undated (Box 192, Folder 2)
  - Tulsa, OK Chapter: Newsletter [2/2], undated (Box 192, Folder 3)
  - Tulsa, OK Chapter: Press Clippings, undated (Box 192, Folder 4)
  - Seattle, WA Chapter (#3), 1940-1949 (Box 192, Folder 5)
  - Milwaukee, Wisc. Chapter (#198), 1950-1959 (Box 192, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Chapter Information, undated (Box 192, Folder 7)
  - AVC Chapter Information Cards, 1960-1970 (Box 192, Folder 8)
  - Prospective Chapters, 1960-1990 (Box 192, Folder 9)
  - Membership Dues Lists, Various Chapters, 1960-1990 (Box 192, Folder 10)
- Membership, 1946-2000; MS2144 Series 10
  This series includes lists of members, membership data, membership appeals, and correspondence with members. It also includes materials relating to fundraising from individuals. (Fundraising from foundations is in Series 6.)
  - AVC Letter to Colleges, 1966 (Box 193, Folder 1)
  - Ballots, 1975-1985 (Box 193, Folder 2)
  - Browne, E. Wayles - Memorial Contributions, 1980 (Box 193, Folder 3)
  - Chapter Membership Data, 1947-1952 (Box 193, Folder 4)
  - Contributors, 1946-1969 (Box 193, Folder 5)
  - Committee of 500, 1978-1979 (Box 193, Folder 6)
  - Committee of 500, 1978-1979; Series 10 (Box 259, Folder 18)
  - Direct-mail Fundraising, 1971 (Box 193, Folder 7)
  - Eligibility for Membership, 1949-1953 (Box 193, Folder 8)
  - Honorary Members, 1949-1954 (Box 193, Folder 9)
  - Life Insurance Plan for Members, undated (Box 193, Folder 10)
  - Members: A - Ay, 1954-1988 (Box 193, Folder 11)
  - Members: B - Bi [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 193, Folder 12)
  - Members: B - Bi [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 194, Folder 1)
  - Members: Bl - By [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 194, Folder 2)
  - Members: Bl - By [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 194, Folder 3)
  - Members: C - Cu [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 194, Folder 4)
  - Members: C - Cu [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 194, Folder 5)
  - Members: D - Ei [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 194, Folder 6)
  - Members: D - Ei [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 194, Folder 7)
  - Members: El - Fl [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 195, Folder 1)
  - Members: El - Fl [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 195, Folder 2)
  - Members: Fo - Gl [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 195, Folder 3)
  - Members: Fo - Gl [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 195, Folder 4)
  - Members: Go - Gu [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 195, Folder 5)
  - Members: Go - Gu [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 195, Folder 6)
  - Members: Ho - Jo [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 196, Folder 1)
  - Members: Ho - Jo [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 196, Folder 2)
  - Members: H - Ho [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 196, Folder 3)
  - Members: H - Ho [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 196, Folder 4)
  - Members: Ka - Ku [1/3], 1954-1988 (Box 196, Folder 5)
  - Members: Ka - Ku [2/3], 1954-1988 (Box 196, Folder 6)
  - Members: Ka - Ku [3/3], 1954-1988 (Box 197, Folder 1)
  - Members: La - Le [1/3], 1954-1988 (Box 197, Folder 2)
  - Members: La - Le [2/3], 1954-1988 (Box 197, Folder 3)
  - Members: La - Le [3/3], 1954-1988 (Box 197, Folder 4)
  - Members: Li - Ly, 1954-1988 (Box 197, Folder 5)
  - Members: Ma - Me [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 197, Folder 6)
  - Members: Ma - Me [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 197, Folder 7)
  - Members: McN - My [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 197, Folder 8)
  - Members: McN - My [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 198, Folder 1)
  - Members: Na - Pe [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 198, Folder 2)
  - Members: Na - Pe [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 198, Folder 3)
  - Members: Pe - Pr, 1954-1988 (Box 198, Folder 4)
  - Members: Q - Re, 1954-1988 (Box 198, Folder 5)
  - Members: Ri - Ro, 1954-1988 (Box 198, Folder 6)
  - Members: Sa - Sm [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 199, Folder 1)
  - Members: Sa - Sm [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 199, Folder 2)
  - Members: Si - Sz [1/3], 1954-1988 (Box 199, Folder 3)
  - Members: Si - Sz [2/3], 1954-1988 (Box 199, Folder 4)
  - Members: Si - Sz [3/3], 1954-1988 (Box 199, Folder 5)
  - Members: Ta - Vy [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 199, Folder 6)
  - Members: Ta - Vy [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 200, Folder 1)
  - Members: Wa - Wh, 1954-1988 (Box 200, Folder 2)
  - Members: Wi - Z [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 200, Folder 3)
  - Members: Wi - Z [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 200, Folder 4)
  - Members: A - D [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 200, Folder 5)
  - Members: A - D [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 200, Folder 6)
  - Members: E - J [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 200, Folder 7)
  - Members: E - J [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 201, Folder 1)
  - Members: K - M [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 201, Folder 2)
  - Members: K - M [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 201, Folder 3)
  - Members: N - R, 1954-1988 (Box 201, Folder 4)
  - Members: S - Z [1/2], 1954-1988 (Box 201, Folder 5)
  - Members: S - Z [2/2], 1954-1988 (Box 201, Folder 6)
  - Member Contributions, 1949-1986 (Box 201, Folder 7)
  - Membership Appeals, 1957-2001 (Box 202, Folder 1)
  - Membership Correspondence, 1974-1978 (Box 202, Folder 2)
  - Membership Correspondence [1/2], 1979-1980 (Box 202, Folder 3)
  - Membership Correspondence [2/2], 1979-1980 (Box 202, Folder 4)
  - Membership Correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 202, Folder 5)
  - Membership Correspondence, 1988-2000 (Box 202, Folder 6)
  - Membership Correspondence - A, 1971-1972 (Box 203, Folder 1)
  - Membership Correspondence - B, 1971-1972 (Box 203, Folder 2)
  - Membership Correspondence - C, 1970-1972 (Box 203, Folder 3)
  - Membership Correspondence - D, 1971-1972 (Box 203, Folder 4)
  - Membership Correspondence - E, 1971-1982 (Box 203, Folder 5)
  - Membership Correspondence - F, 1971-1973 (Box 203, Folder 6)
  - Membership Correspondence - G, 1972-1975 (Box 203, Folder 7)
  - Membership Correspondence - H - I, 1970-1974 (Box 203, Folder 8)
  - Membership Correspondence - J - K, 1970-1971 (Box 203, Folder 9)
  - Membership Correspondence - L - M, 1971-1975 (Box 203, Folder 10)
  - Membership Correspondence - N - P, 1971-1974 (Box 204, Folder 1)
  - Membership Correspondence - R - S, 1970-1974 (Box 204, Folder 2)
  - Membership Correspondence - T - Z, 1970-1975 (Box 204, Folder 3)
  - Membership Reports, 1961-1975 (Box 204, Folder 4)
  - Membership Reports [1/2], 1976-1989 (Box 204, Folder 5)
  - Membership Reports [2/2], 1976-1989 (Box 204, Folder 6)
  - Membership Requests, 1976-1977 (Box 205, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Membership Lists, undated (Box 205, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Membership Lists, undated; Series 10 (Box 259, Folder 19)
  - National Advisory Board and National Advisory Council, 1962-1983 (Box 205, Folder 3)
  - National Officers, 1959-1981 (Box 205, Folder 4)
  - National Officers, 1948-1980 (Box 205, Folder 5)
  - National Membership Lists, undated (Box 205, Folder 6)
  - Progressive Magazine Membership Exchange, 1952-1954 (Box 205, Folder 7)
  - Special Contributors, 1954-1955 (Box 205, Folder 8)
  - Special Membership Appeal, 1961 (Box 205, Folder 9)
  - WVF Contributors, 1983-1984 (Box 205, Folder 10)
- Clippings, 1932-2001; MS2144 Series 11
  This series includes newspaper articles written by AVC staff -- primarily but not exclusively from Stars and Stripes newspaper -- as well as articles that feature AVC in newspapers and magazines. The largest quantity of articles featuring AVC are in several bound scrapbooks compiled during the 1940s.
  - Articles about AVC, 1945-1947 (Box 206, Folder 1)
  - Articles about AVC, 1948-1964 (Box 206, Folder 2)
  - Articles about AVC, 1965-2001 (Box 206, Folder 3)
  - AVC Convention Articles, 1951 (Box 206, Folder 4)
  - Communism, 1946-1948 (Box 206, Folder 5)
  - Medgar Evers - Clippings and Correspondence, 1963 (Box 206, Folder 6)
  - Reviews - "Women Veterans: America's Forgotten Heroines", undated (Box 206, Folder 7)
  - Ronald Reagan/AVC Press Release and Reagan Article on Fascism in AVC Bulletin, undated (Box 206, Folder 8)
  - Rosen Articles, 1977-1978 (Box 206, Folder 9)
  - Stars and Stripes Articles, 1978-1979 (Box 206, Folder 10)
  - Stars and Stripes Articles, 1980 (Box 206, Folder 11)
  - Stars and Stripes Articles, 1981 (Box 206, Folder 12)
  - Stars and Stripes Articles, 1982 (Box 207, Folder 1)
  - Stars and Stripes Articles, 1983 (Box 207, Folder 2)
  - Stars and Stripes Articles, 1984 (Box 207, Folder 3)
  - Stars and Stripes Articles, 1985 (Box 207, Folder 4)
  - Stars and Stripes Articles, 1986 (Box 207, Folder 5)
  - Stars and Stripes Articles, 1987 (Box 207, Folder 6)
  - Stars and Stripes Articles, 1989-1994 (Box 207, Folder 7)
  - Stars and Stripes Articles, 1995 (Box 254, Folder 11)
  - Tyler Articles, 1978-1994 (Box 207, Folder 8)
  - Willenz Articles, 1974-1985 (Box 207, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook, 1936-1939 (Box 208, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1932-1936 (Box 208, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1940-1944 (Box 209, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1947-1948 (Box 209, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1943-1945 (Box 210, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1945-1946 (Box 210, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1945 (Box 211, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1946 (Box 212, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1946 (Box 212, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1947 (Box 213, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1946 (Box 213, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1946 (Box 214, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1946 (Box 214, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1946 (Box 214, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1947 (Box 215, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1946-1947 (Box 215, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1955-1956 (Box 216, Folder 1)
- World Veterans Federation, 1953-2002; MS2144 Series 12
  This series includes programs, reports, correspondence, and subject files relating to American Veterans Committee members' activities as part of the World Veterans Federation. It features correspondence from AVC leaders Paul Cooke, Herbert Will, and June Willenz, and well as official programs and documents from WVF General Assemblies. (WVF photographs are in series 13.)
  - 4th International Conference of Legislation Concerning Veterans and Victims of War, undated (Box 217, Folder 1)
  - 5th General Assembly - Vienna, 1954 (Box 217, Folder 2)
  - 12th General Assembly - The Hague, 1967 (Box 217, Folder 3)
  - 2nd Conference of African Veterans Affairs, 1962 (Box 217, Folder 4)
  - 2nd International Conference on Peace and Security in the Mediterranean-Catania, 1998 (Box 217, Folder 5)
  - 2nd Meeting of the Council - Bangkok, 1962 (Box 217, Folder 6)
  - 2nd World Meeting of War Veterans, Resistants, and War Victims, 1986 (Box 217, Folder 7)
  - 4th General Assembly - The Hague, 1953 (Box 217, Folder 8)
  - 4th International Conference on Legislation Concerning Veterans and War Victims, 1977 (Box 217, Folder 9)
  - 5th General Assembly - Vienna, 1954 (Box 217, Folder 10)
  - 5th International Conference on Legislation Concerning Veterans and War Victims - Bad Ischl, Austria, 1988 (Box 218, Folder 1)
  - 6th General Assembly - Brussels, 1956 (Box 218, Folder 2)
  - 6th International Conference on Legislation Concerning Veterans and Victims of War, 1994 (Box 218, Folder 3)
  - 6th Legislation Conference, 1994 (Box 218, Folder 4)
  - 7th General Assembly - Berlin, 1957 (Box 218, Folder 5)
  - 8th General Assembly - Rome, 1959 (Box 218, Folder 6)
  - 9th General Assembly - Paris, 1961 (Box 218, Folder 7)
  - 10th General Assembly - Copenhagen [1/3], 1963 (Box 219, Folder 1)